Finding Aid for Emil Lorch Papers 1891-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Correspondence 1891-1962, 9.5 linear feet
  - March 1948 (Box 6)
    [6-58]
  - April 1948 (Box 6)
    [6-59]
  - May 1948 (Box 6)
    [6-60]
  - June 1948 (Box 6)
    [6-61]
  - July-August 1948 (Box 6)
    [6-62]
  - September 1948 (Box 6)
    [6-63]
  - October 1948 (Box 6)
    [6-64]
  - November 1948 (Box 6)
    [6-65]
  - December and 1948 undated (Box 6)
    [6-66]
  - January 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-1]
  - February 1945 (Box 7)
    [7-2]
  - March 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-3]
  - April 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-4]
  - May 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-5]
  - June 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-6]
  - July 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-7]
  - August 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-8]
  - September 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-9]
  - October 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-10]
  - November 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-11]
  - December 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-12]
  - Undated 1949 (Box 7)
    [7-13]
  - January 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-14]
  - February 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-15]
  - March 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-16]
  - April 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-17]
  - May 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-18]
  - June 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-19]
  - July 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-20]
  - August 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-21]
  - September 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-22]
  - October 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-23]
  - November 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-24]
  - December 1950 (Box 7)
    [7-25]
  - January 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-26]
  - February 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-27]
  - March 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-28]
  - April 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-29]
  - May 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-30]
  - June 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-31]
  - July 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-32]
  - August 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-33]
  - September 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-34]
  - October 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-35]
  - November 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-36]
  - December and undated 1951 (Box 7)
    [7-37]
  - Undated 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-38]
  - January 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-39]
  - February 1-14, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-40]
  - February 15-28, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-41]
  - March 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-42]
  - April 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-43]
  - May 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-44]
  - June 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-45]
  - July 1-14, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-46]
  - July 15-31, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-47]
  - August 1-14, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-48]
  - August 15-31, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-49]
  - September 1-14, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-50]
  - September 15-30, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-51]
  - October 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-52]
  - November 1-14, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-53]
  - November 15-30, 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-54]
  - December 1952 (Box 7)
    [7-55]
  - Undated 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-56]
  - January 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-57]
  - February 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-58]
  - February 15-28, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-59]
  - March 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-60]
  - March 15-31, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-61]
  - April 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-62]
  - April 15-30, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-63]
  - May 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-64]
  - May 15-31, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-65]
  - June 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-66]
  - June 15-30, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-67]
  - July 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-68]
  - July 15-31, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-69]
  - August 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-70]
  - August 15-31, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-71]
  - September 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-72]
  - September 15-30, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-73]
  - October 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-74]
  - October 15-31, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-75]
  - November 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-76]
  - November 15-30, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-77]
  - December 1-14, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-78]
  - December 15-31, 1953 (Box 7)
    [7-79]
  - Undated 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-1]
  - January 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-2]
  - January 15-30, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-3]
  - February 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-4]
  - February 15-28, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-5]
  - March 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-6]
  - March 15-31, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-7]
  - April 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-8]
  - April 15-30, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-9]
  - May 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-10]
  - May 15-31, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-11]
  - June 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-12]
  - July 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-13]
  - July 15-31, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-14]
  - August 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-15]
  - August 15-31, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-16]
  - September 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-17]
  - September 15-30, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-18]
  - October 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-19]
  - October 15-31, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-20]
  - November 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-21]
  - November 15-30, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-22]
  - December 1-14, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-23]
  - December 15-30, 1954 (Box 8)
    [8-24]
  - Undated 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-25]
  - January 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-26]
  - January 15-31, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-27]
  - February 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-28]
  - February 15-28, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-29]
  - March 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-30]
  - March 15-31, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-31]
  - April 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-32]
  - April 15-30, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-33]
  - May 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-34]
  - June 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-35]
  - July 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-36]
  - August 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-37]
  - August 15-31, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-38]
  - September 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-39]
  - September 15-30, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-40]
  - October 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-41]
  - October 15-31, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-42]
  - November 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-43]
  - November 15-30, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-44]
  - December 1-14, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-45]
  - December 15-31, 1955 (Box 8)
    [8-46]
  - Undated 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-47]
  - January 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-48]
  - January 15-31, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-49]
  - February 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-50]
  - February 15-29, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-51]
  - March 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-52]
  - March 15-31, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-53]
  - April 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-54]
  - April 15-30, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-55]
  - May 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-56]
  - June 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-57]
  - June 15-30, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-58]
  - July 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-59]
  - July 15-31, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-60]
  - August 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-61]
  - August 15-31, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-62]
  - September 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-63]
  - September 15-30, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-64]
  - October 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-65]
  - October 15-31, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-66]
  - November 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-67]
  - November 15-30, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-68]
  - December 1-14, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-69]
  - December 15-31, 1956 (Box 8)
    [8-70]
  - January 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-1]
  - January .15-31 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-2]
  - February 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-3]
  - February 15-28, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-4]
  - March 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-5]
  - 15-31 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-6]
  - April 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-7]
  - April 15-30, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-8]
  - May 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-9]
  - May 15-31, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-10]
  - June 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-11]
  - June 15-30, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-12]
  - July 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-13]
  - July 15-31, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-14]
  - August 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-15]
  - August 15-31, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-16]
  - September 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-17]
  - October 1-14, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-18]
  - October 15-31, 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-19]
  - November 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-20]
  - December 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-21]
  - Undated 1957 (Box 9)
    [9-22]
  - January 1-14, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-23]
  - January 15-31, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-24]
  - February 1-14, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-25]
  - February 15-28, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-26]
  - March 1-14, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-27]
  - March 15-31, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-28]
  - April 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-29]
  - May 1-14, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-30]
  - May 15-31, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-31]
  - June 1-14, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-32]
  - June 15-30, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-33]
  - July 1-14, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-34]
  - July 15-31, 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-35]
  - August 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-36]
  - September 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-37]
  - October 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-38]
  - November 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-39]
  - December 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-40]
  - Undated 1958 (Box 9)
    [9-41]
  - January 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-42]
  - January 15-31, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-43]
  - February 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-44]
  - February 15-28, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-45]
  - March 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-46]
  - March 15-31, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-47]
  - April 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-48]
  - April 15-30, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-49]
  - May 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-50]
  - May 15-31, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-51]
  - June 1-11, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-52]
  - June 15-30, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-53]
  - July 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-54]
  - July 15-31, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-55]
  - August 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-56]
  - September 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-57]
  - October 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-58]
  - October 15-31, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-59]
  - November 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-60]
  - November 15-30, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-61]
  - December 1-14, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-62]
  - December 15-31, 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-63]
  - Undated 1959 (Box 9)
    [9-64]
  - January 1-14, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-1]
  - January 15-31, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-2]
  - February 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-3]
  - March 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-4]
  - April 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-5]
  - May 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-6]
  - June 1-14, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-7]
  - June 15-30, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-8]
  - July 1-14, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-9]
  - July 15-31, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-10]
  - August 1-14, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-11]
  - August 15-31, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-12]
  - September 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-13]
  - October 1-14, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-14]
  - October 15-31, 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-15]
  - November 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-16]
  - December 1960 (Box 10)
    [10-17]
  - January 1-14, 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-18]
  - January 15-31, 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-19]
  - February 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-20]
  - March 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-21]
  - April 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-22]
  - May 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-23]
  - June 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-24]
  - July 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-25]
  - August-September 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-26]
  - October-November 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-27]
  - December 1961 (Box 10)
    [10-28]
  - January 1962 (Box 10)
    [10-29]
  - February-April 1962 (Box 10)
    [10-30]
  - May-July 1962 (Box 10)
    [10-31]
  - August-December 1962 (Box 10)
    [10-32]
  - Undated (Box 10)
    [10-33]
  - Undated (Box 10)
    [10-34]
  - Undated (Box 10)
    [10-35]
  - Undated (Box 10)
    [10-36]
  - Undated (Box 10)
    [10-37]
- Published articles
  Published Articles consists of architectural articles and published memorabilia important to Lorch.
  - Periodicals containing articles by Lorch and other architects, 2 folders (Box 10)
- Architectural League of America 1902-1912, 1939-1945, 8 folders
  The Architectural League of America series includes materials from the period of Lorch's most active involvement and consists of executive board records, notes, historical information, and convention proceedings. This series also includes correspondence of Frank C. Baldwin during the period when he was president, 1908-1909.
  - Executive Board papers 1906-1911 (Box 11)
    [11-1]
  - Correspondence of Frank C. Baldwin, president 1908-1909 (Box 11)
    [11-1a]
  - Notes and drafts of writings (Box 11)
    [11-2]
  - Published material, including proceedings 1902-1912 (Box 11)
    [11-3]
  - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
    [11-4; 11-5]
  - Proceedings of the Tenth Convention (original) 1911 (Box 11)
    [11-6]
  - Correspondence of the American Institute of Architects regarding 1939-1945 (Box 11)
    [11-7]
- University of Michigan School of Architecture 1909-1927, 1956, 4 folders
  The small University of Michigan School of Architecture series consists of budgets and other information about the development of the architecture program at the University of Michigan.
  - Papers concerning the architecture building 1920-1923 (Box 11)
    [11-8]
  - Papers concerning the development of courses in decorative design (Box 11)
    [11-9]
  - Budgets 1909-1927 (Box 11)
    [11-10]
  - Notes on its collections from 1906-1936, 1956 (Box 11)
    [11-11]
- Notes for Lecture and Addresses, 19 folders
  Lecture and Addresses is a series of notes, arranged by broad topic, and pertaining to architectural history. This series also includes some information about Michigan buildings.
  - Modern Architecture circa 1916 (Box 11)
    [11-12; 11-13; 11-14]
  - Federal Period (Box 11)
    [11-15]
  - Gothic Architecture (Box 11)
    [11-16]
  - Industrial Architecture (Box 11)
    [11-17]
  - Pioneer Period (Box 11)
    [11-18]
  - Rheims Cathedral (Box 11)
    [11-19]
  - Various Modern Buildings in Michigan (Box 11)
    [11-20]
  - Design circa 1902 (Box 11)
    [11-21]
  - Greek Architecture (Box 11)
    [11-22; 11-23; 11-24]
  - Building a New House (radio lectures) 1934-1936 (Box 11)
    [11-25]
  - History of Architecture 1920 (Box 11)
    [11-26]
  - History of Architecture 1921 (Box 11)
    [11-27]
  - History of Michigan Architecture (Introductory) (Box 11)
    [11-28]
  - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
    [11-29]
  - Miscellaneous (speeches) (Box 11)
    [11-30]
- American Institute of Architects 1952-1957, 9 folders
  The American Institute of Architects series consists of correspondence, 1952-1957, and information relating to the Michigan chapter of the AIA.
  - Committee on the Preservation of Historic Buildings
    - Correspondence and other papers 1952 (Box 11)
      [11-31]
    - Correspondence and other papers 1953 (Box 11)
      [11-32; 11-33]
    - Correspondence and other papers 1954 (Box 11)
      [11-34]
    - Correspondence and other papers 1955 (Box 11)
      [11-35]
    - Correspondence and other papers 1957 (Box 11)
      [11-36; 11-37; 11-38]
  - Michigan Chapter of the AIA
    - Collected information with material on Frank C. Baldwin and the AIA (Box 11)
      [11-39]
- Research Notes and collected material, 22 folders
  Research notes and collected material is a valuable resource for the information accumulated by Lorch from different sources and pertaining to the history of Michigan architecture and to other related topics.
  - History of Michigan Architecture
    - Greek Revival (Box 12)
      [12-1]
    - Business Structures (Box 12)
      [12-2]
    - Churches (Box 12)
      [12-3]
    - Forts (Box 12)
      [12-4]
    - Log Structures (Box 12)
      [12-5]
    - Romanesque and Gothic Revival (Box 12)
      [12-6]
    - Taverns, Inns, Hotels (Box 12)
      [12-7]
    - General notes and drafts (Box 12)
      [12-8; 12-9]
    - Notebook containing sketches and miscellaneous notes on Michigan architecture (Box 12)
      [12-10.1]
    - Newspaper clippings relating to historic Michigan houses (Box 12)
      [12-10.2]
    - Bibliographies pertaining to Michigan architecture (Box 12)
      [12-10.3]
  - Architects and other topics
    - Irving K. Pond (Box 12)
      [12-11]
    - Louis H. Sullivan (Box 12)
      [12-12]
    - George Mason (Box 12)
      [12-13]
    - William Le Baron Jenney (Box 12)
      [12-14]
    - Gordon W. Lloyd (Box 12)
      [12-15]
    - Michigan architects (Box 12)
      [12-16]
    - Grand Portage, Minn. (Box 12)
      [12-17; 12-18]
    - Grand Portage, Minn. (Description of fur trading posts) (Box 12)
      [12-19; 12-20]
    - Grand Portage, Minn. (Descriptions of Fort Williams) (Box 12)
      [12-21]
    - Grand Portage, Minn. (History of Buildings) (Box 12)
      [12-22]
- Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS) 1933-1937, 25 folders
  The Historic American Buildings Survey contains general information about the survey with specific files on Lorch's work with the midwest region of the HABS.
  - Miscellaneous papers 1936-1937, 3 folders (Box 12)
    [12-23; 12-24; 12-25]
  - General information (Box 12)
    [12-31]
  - Proposed surveys (Box 12)
    [12-32]
  - Press releases (Box 12)
    [12-33]
  - Missouri (Pleitsch-Trueblood) (Box 12)
    [12-33.1]
  - Advisory Committees (Box 12)
    [12-34]
  - Wisconsin (Guth) (Box 12)
    [12-35]
  - Inventory Blanks (Box 12)
    [12-36; 12-37]
  - Historical and descriptive data (Box 12)
    [12-38]
  - Michigan (Hughes) (Box 12)
    [12-39]
  - Payroll (Box 12)
    [12-40; 12-41]
  - Printed materials (Box 12)
    [12-42; 12-43; 12-44]
  - Michigan Buildings papers (Box 12)
    [12-45]
  - District Advisory Board (Box 12)
    [12-46; 12-47]
- Miscellaneous organizational interests, 3 folders
  Miscellaneous organizational interests has material from Lorch's involvement with the Ann Arbor Art Association, the Michigan Society of Architects, and the Michigan State Board for Registration of Architects.
  - Ann Arbor Art Association; history and miscellaneous (Box 12)
    [12-48]
  - Michigan Society of Architects. "Michigan Architects and the War," 1947 (Box 12)
    [12-49]
  - Michigan State Board for Registration of Architects (Box 12)
    [12-50]
- Historic Michigan buildings, 5 linear feet
  Historic Michigan Buildings is a large series of collected information about Michigan structures done for the Michigan Historic Buildings Survey. The series is arranged alphabetically by county, then by name of city. A significant portion of these files relate to the restoration of the fort and other buildings on Mackinac Island and to the historic homes of Ann Arbor and Detroit, to the Judge Dexter home in Dexter, to various structures in Dearborn, and to the early buildings of the University of Michigan.
  - Alger County (Box 13)
    [13-1]
    (See also Grand Island)
  - Alpena County (Box 13)
    [13-2]
  - Barry County (Box 13)
    [13-3]
  - Baraga County (Box 13)
    [13-4]
  - Bay County (Box 13)
    [13-5]
  - Beaver Island (Box 13)
    [13-6]
  - Berrien County
    - Coloma (Box 13)
      [13-7]
    - Fort St. Joseph (Box 13)
      [13-8]
    - Niles (Box 13)
      [13-9]
    - St. Joseph (Box 13)
      [13-10]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-11]
  - Bois Blanc Island (Box 13)
    [13-12]
  - Branch County: Coldwater State Training School (Box 13)
    [13-13]
  - Calhoun County
    - Albion
      - Albion College (Box 13)
        [13-14 and 13-15]
      - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
        [13-16]
    - Battle Creek (Box 13)
      [13-17]
    - Marshall
      - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
        [13-18 and 13-19]
      - Court House (New) (Box 13)
        [13-20]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-21]
  - Cass County (Box 13)
    [13-22]
  - Charlevoix County
    (See also Beaver Island)
    - Charlevoix (Box 13)
      [13-23]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-24]
  - Cheboygan County: Mackinaw City, Fort Michilimackinac (Box 13)
    [13-25 and 13-26]
  - Chippewa County: Sault Ste. Marie
    - Johnston House (Box 13)
      [13-27]
    - Power House (Box 13)
      [13-28]
    - Schoolcraft House (Box 13)
      [13-29]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-30]
    - {See also Drummond Island} (Box 13)
  - Clinton County (Box 13)
    [13-31]
  - Delta County (Box 13)
    [13-32]
  - Drummond Island: Fort Collyer (Box 13)
    [13-33]
  - Emmet County: Petoskey (Box 13)
    [13-34]
    (See also Cheboygan County for Fort Michilimackinac)
  - Genesee County
    - Fenton (Box 13)
      [13-35]
    - Flint (Box 13)
      [13-36]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-37]
  - Gogebic County: Gogebic Iron Range history (Joseph Gill) (Box 13)
    [13-39]
  - Grand Island (Box 13)
    [13-40]
  - Gratiot County: Alma (Box 13)
    [13-41]
  - Hillsdale County
    - Hillsdale: Hillsdale College (Box 13)
      [13-42]
    - Jonesville (Box 13)
      [13-43]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-44]
  - Houghton County: Hancock (Box 13)
    [13-45]
  - Huron County
    - Harbor Beach (Box 13)
      [13-46]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-47]
  - Ingham County
    - East Lansing: Michigan State University (Box 13)
      [13-48]
    - Lansing (Box 13)
      [13-49]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-50]
  - Isabella County (Box 13)
    [13-51]
  - Jackson County
    - Brooklyn (Box 13)
      [13-52]
    - Grass Lake (Box 13)
      [13-53]
    - Jackson (Box 13)
      [13-54]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-55]
  - Kalamazoo County
    - Galesburg (Box 13)
      [13-56]
    - Kalamazoo
      - State Hospital (Box 13)
        [13-57]
      - Upjohn Company, Brookledge (Box 13)
        [13-58]
      - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
        [13-59]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-60]
  - Keweenaw County
    - Copper Harbor: Fort Wilkins (Box 13)
      [13-61 to 13-63]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-64]
  - Kent County
    - Grand Rapids (Box 13)
      [13-65 and 13-66]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-67]
  - Lapeer County (Box 13)
    [13-68]
  - Lenawee County
    - Adrian (Box 13)
      [13-69]
    - Clinton (Box 13)
      [13-70]
    - Tecumseh
      - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
        [13-71]
      - St. Peter's Episcopal Church (Box 13)
        [13-72]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-73]
  - Livingston County
    - Brighton (Box 13)
      [13-74]
    - Howell (Box 13)
      [13-75]
    - Rushton (Box 13)
      [13-76]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
      [13-77]
  - Luce County (Box 13)
    [13-78]
  - Mackinac County
    (see also Bois Blanc Island)
    - Mackinac Island
      - General information (Box 13)
        [13-79 to 13-82]
      - Restoration policies (Box 13)
        [13-83]
      - HABS building evaluations (Box 13)
        [13-84]
      - Notes made for Mackinac restoration (Box 13)
        [13-85]
      - Correspondence concerning restorations 1937-1957 1947-1949 (Box 14)
        [14-1 to 14-18]
      - Source materials (Box 14)
        [14-19 to 14-25]
      - Pictures and clippings (Box 14)
        [14-26]
      - John J. Astor House (Box 14)
        [14-27]
      - Beaumont House
        - Notes (Box 14)
          [14-28 to 14-35]
        - Historical data (Box 14)
          [14-36 to 14-39]
        - Photostats (Box 14)
          [14-40]
        - Layouts and architectural studies (Box 14)
          [14-41]
        - Sketches (Box 14)
          [14-42]
        - Blueprints (Box 14)
          [14-43]
        - Printed materials (Box 14)
          [14-44]
        - General (Box 14)
          [14-45]
        - Financial assessment of restoration (Box 15)
          [15-1]
        - Correspondence relating to restoration 1948-1956, 1952-1953 (Box 15)
          [15-2 to 15-11]
      - Biddle House
        - Notes (Box 15)
          [15-12 to 15-15]
        - Pictures and clippings (Box 15)
          [15-16]
        - Correspondence 1927-1960 (Box 15)
          [15-17 to 15-20]
      - Fort Mackinac (Box 15)
        [15-21]
      - Grand Hotel (Box 15)
        [15-22]
      - Old Mission Church (Box 15)
        [15-23]
    - St. Ignace (Box 15)
      [15-24]
  - Macomb County
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      [15-25]
    - Warren (Box 15)
      [15-26]
  - Manistee County (Box 15)
    [15-27]
  - Marquette County
    - Gwinn (Box 15)
      [15-28]
    - Marquette (Box 15)
      [15-29]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      [15-30]
  - Mason County: Ludington (Box 15)
    [15-31]
  - Mecosta County
    - Big Rapids (Box 15)
      [15-32]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      [15-33]
  - Menominee County: Menominee (Box 15)
    [15-34]
  - Monroe County
    - Monroe (Box 15)
      [15-35]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      [15-36]
  - Muskegon County: Muskegon (Box 15)
    [15-37]
  - Oakland County
    - Bloomfield Hills
      - General (Box 15)
        [15-38]
      - Cranbrook (Box 15)
        [15-39]
    - Drayton Plains: Moses Wisner House (Box 15)
      [15-40]
    - Farmington Hills: Botsford Tavern (Box 15)
      [15-41]
    - Franklin (Box 15)
      [15-42]
    - Rochester (Box 15)
      [15-43]
    - Walled Lake (Box 15)
      [15-44]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      [15-45]
  - Ottawa County
    - Holland
      - Hope College (Box 15)
        [15-46]
      - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
        [15-47]
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      [15-48]
  - Presque Isle County (Box 15)
    [15-49]
  - Saginaw County: Saginaw (Box 15)
    [15-50]
  - St. Clair County
    - Marysville (Box 15)
      [15-51]
    - Port Huron (Box 15)